co-operativebank.co.uk 2012-11-28

# The Co-operative Bank | Privacy

Bank > Privacy 

The privacy of The Co-operative Bank's customers is very important to us, and how we deal with personal information is outlined in our terms and conditions. We hope the way in which we gather and use your personal information addresses and respects any concerns you may have:

**We will only use the personal information we gather:**

  * In the normal course of our business to provide the products and services you have requested.
  * To identify you when you contact us.
  * To determine if we can offer you a better service or more relevant products.
  * To send you e-mail updates of service changes which are important to you or which we feel may be of interest to you.
  * For credit assessment, to review the conduct of and to administer/operate your accounts.
  * For statistical analysis, including automated techniques (eg behaviour and credit scoring) and to monitor and analyse our business.

**We will disclose your personal information only to:**

  * Our agents and sub-contractors to administer and operate your account or to conduct our business.
  * The insurer of any payment or card protection cover which you take out in connection with your account.
  * Our licensed credit reference agency who may keep a record of any search we make and your personal information may be shared with and used by other lenders in assessing applications from you or members of your household.
  * Any person to whom we transfer our rights or obligations under this agreement.
  * For debt tracing or fraud prevention.
  * To help desk advisers, minicom/typetalk operators or their equivalent.
  * If required or compelled to do so by law.

For full details of how your information may be used for credit reference and fraud prevention purposes by The Co-operative Bank and the Credit Reference Agencies please read our guide on personal data.

**Cookies**

Cookies are small pieces of information sent to your computer or browsing device when you access a website. These files are not computer programmes and cannot be used to cause damage to your computer. They are often essential to helping us provide you with a good on-line experience. Some areas of the site may not function correctly without the use of cookies. 

We will not use cookies to 

  * Store personal information on your hard drive
  * Send personal information to 3rd parties

By accessing this website, you agree that we can place cookies on your device. You can disable cookies completely by changing your browser settings; however some areas of the site will not be accessible or may not function properly. You will not be able to access internet banking if cookies are disabled. 

**Further information about our cookies**

You can find out more about how we use cookies, including how to disable them here.
